<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Meta-Logical Solutions</title>
    <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Meta-Logical Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 15:37:57 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of Metallurgical Reactions</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/kinetics-of-metallurgical-reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/kinetics-of-metallurgical-reactions/</guid>
      <description>Some basic information here.
Research Highlights  Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2000). Redox equilibria and kinetics of gas-slag reactions. Metallurgical and Materials Transactions B - Process Metallurgy and Materials Processing Science, 31 (5): 937-943.
 Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (1995). Hot issues in smelting kinetics. In: 2nd Australian Melt Chemistry Symposium, 69-75.
 Sayadyaghoubi, Y., Tran, T., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (1994). Kinetics of redox reactions in calcium ferrite melts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor Elements</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/minor-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/minor-elements/</guid>
      <description>Management of Minor Elements &amp;amp; Value Recovery from Low Grade Ores &amp;amp; By-products
Research Highlights  Chen, C., Zhang, L., Wright, S., and Jahanshahi, S. (2006) Thermodynamic modelling of minor elements in copper smelting processes. In: F. Kongoli, and R. G. Reddy; Sohn International Symposium on Advanced Processing of Metals and Materials: Principles, Technologies and Industrial Practices, 335-348.
 Norgate, T. E. and Jahanshahi, S. (2010). Low grade ores - smelt, leach or concentrate?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process Modelling</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/process-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/process-modelling/</guid>
      <description>We help optimize metallurgical performance, management of impurities, metal recovery, refractory life and fuel consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharif Jahanshahi PhD, DIC</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/team/sharif-jahanshahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/team/sharif-jahanshahi/</guid>
      <description>With over 30 years experience in R&amp;amp;D across the high temperature processing of ferrous and base metals, covering the thermodynamics metallurgical systems, process modelling and development. Sharif has been closely connected with the leading edge of process metallurgy R&amp;amp;D and the people that drive it.
Sharif has been a Fellow of Australasian Institute of Mining Metallurgy. He is currently an Adjunct Professor at the University of New South Wales and Associate Editor of the Journal of Sustainable Metallurgy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Metallurgy</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/training/basic-metallurgy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/training/basic-metallurgy/</guid>
      <description>We help teams revise basic principles of metallurgy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Studies</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/feasibility-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/feasibility-studies/</guid>
      <description>We help companies develop and evaluate energy efficient process flowsheets for the lower-grade ores of the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pari Osivand PhD, DEnvSc</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/team/pari-osivand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/team/pari-osivand/</guid>
      <description>Pari is a biochemist by training and has extensive research experience in various aspects of algae growth, including nutrient accumulation and transfer in biomass species. She has also worked on research projects ranging from identifying the Ross River virus to cheese-making bacteria, through a number of universities and research institutes in Australia and the UK.
As an environmental scientist, Pari acquired a deep understanding of the dimensions, complexities and relationships between the physical, human and environmental world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards Zero Waste</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/towards-zero-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/towards-zero-waste/</guid>
      <description>We advise on efficient use of resources and renewable carbonaceous fuels in metallurgical processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sustainability Assessments</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/sustainability-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/services/sustainability-assessments/</guid>
      <description>We facilitate assessment of industrial ecology and sustainability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborators</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/team/collaborators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/team/collaborators/</guid>
      <description>Over the years and through many collaborative projects, we have developed an extensive network of experts, which covers engineering firms and R&amp;amp;D centres in Australia, Europe, South Africa, North America and Japan. MLS can arrange engagement of key engineers and scientists with complementary expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dry Slag Granulation</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/dry-slag-granulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/dry-slag-granulation/</guid>
      <description>Research Highlights All Publications  Jahanshahi, S., Mathieson, J.G., Somerville, M.A., Haque, N., Norgate, T.E., Deev, A., Pan, Y., Xie, D., Ridgeway, P. and Zulli, P., Development of Low-Emission Integrated Steelmaking Process, J. Sustain. Metall., 2015, DOI 10.1007/s40831-015-0008-6.
 Xie, D., Washington, B.M., Norgate, T.E., Jahanshahi, S. (2005) Dry granulation of slags - turning waste into valuable products, Current advances in materials and processes (CAMP-ISIJ), 18(4), 1088-1091.
 Jahanshahi, Sharif; Deev, Alex; Haque, Nawshad; Lu, Liming; Mathieson, John; Norgate, Terry (2014) Current status and future direction of low-emission Integrated Steelmaking Process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Processes</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/life-cycle-assessment-of-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/life-cycle-assessment-of-processes/</guid>
      <description>Research Highlights  Norgate, T.E, Jahanshahi, S., and Rankin, W.J. (2009). Chapter 12 “Metals and Sustainable Development” in Environmental Impact Assessments, pp.355-396, Edited by G. T Halley &amp;amp; Y.T. Fridian, Nova Science Publishers Inc, NY.
 Norgate, T and Jahanshahi, S (2011) Reducing the greenhouse gas footprint of primary metal production: Where should the focus be? Minerals Engineering, 24(14), 1563-1570.
  All Publications  Norgate, T.E, Jahanshahi, S., and Rankin, W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Emission Steelmaking</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/low-emission-steelmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/low-emission-steelmaking/</guid>
      <description>Research Highlights  Jahanshahi, S., Mathieson, J.G., Somerville, M.A., Haque, N., Norgate, T.E., Deev, A., Pan, Y., Xie, D., Ridgeway, P. and Zulli, P., (2015) Development of Low-Emission Integrated Steelmaking Process, J. Sustain. Metall., DOI 10.1007/s40831-015-0008-6.
 Jahanshahi, S and Xie, D (2012) Current status and future direction of CSIRO&amp;rsquo;s dry slag granulation process with waste heat recovery. In: 5th International Congress on the Science and Technology of Steelmaking 2012 (ICS 2012); 1-3 October 2012; Dresden, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Slag Properties and Metallurgical Processes</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/modelling-slag-properties-and-metallurgical-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/modelling-slag-properties-and-metallurgical-processes/</guid>
      <description>Research Highlights  Pan, Yuhua, Sun, Shouyi, Jahanshahi, Sharif (2011) Mathematical modelling of heat transfer in six-in-line electric furnaces for sulphide smelting, Journal of the South African Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, 111 (10), 717-732.
 Zhang, L., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2007) An approach to modeling Al2O3 containing slags with the cell model, Journal of Phase Equilibria and Diffusion, 28 (1), 121-129.
 Zhang, L., Jahanshahi, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/others/</guid>
      <description>Publications  Jahanshahi, S., and Jeffes, J.H.E. (1981), &amp;ldquo;Design of Coils for Levitating Droplets of Metals with Improved Temperature Control Characteristics&amp;rdquo; Trans IMM Sec. C, 1981, Vol. 90, pp. C138-C140.
 Yang, J., Zhang, G., Jahanshahi, S. and Ostrovski, O. (2015) Reduction of a garnieritic laterite ore by CO-CO2 gas mixtures, The Fourteenth International Ferroalloys Congress, INFACON XIV, Kiev, Ukraine, May 31-June 4, 2015, Vol. 2, 518-527.
 Holmes, Ralph; Jahanshahi, Sharif; Law, Jonathan (2013) Research and innovation for the iron ore to carbon steel value chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Properties of Melts</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/properties-of-melts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/properties-of-melts/</guid>
      <description>This includes research covering the thermodynamics of melts, transport properties of slags and the structure and physicochemical properties of slags.
Research Highlights  Sayadyaghoubi, Y., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (1995). Determination of the chemical diffusion of oxygen in liquid iron oxide at 1615oC. Metallurgical and Materials Transactions B - Process Metallurgy and Materials Processing Science, 26B: 795-802.
 Zhang, L., and Jahanshahi, S. (1998). Review and modeling of viscosity of silicate melts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slag-Refractory Interactions</title>
      <link>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/slag-refractory-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://metalogicalsolutions.netlify.com/expertise/slag-refractory-interactions/</guid>
      <description>Research Highlights  Lee, M., Jahanshahi, S. Design and implementation of slag practices for reduction in refractory consumption at BHP steelmaking centres. Scandinavian Journal of Metallurgy. 2001; 30(2):108-112.
 Xie, D., Tran, T., and Jahanshahi, S. (2001). In-situ gravimetric studies of wetting, penetration and wear of refractories by molten slags. High Temperature Materials and Processes, 20 (3-4): 293-301.
  All Publications  Yan, S., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>