<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Meta-Logical Solutions</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Meta-Logical Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 15:37:57 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>​Kinetics of Metallurgical Reactions</title>
      <link>/expertise/kinetics-of-metallurgical-reactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/kinetics-of-metallurgical-reactions/</guid>
      <description>Some basic information here.
Highlights  Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2000). Redox equilibria and kinetics of gas-slag reactions. Metallurgical and Materials Transactions B - Process Metallurgy and Materials Processing Science, 31 (5): 937-943. Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (1995). Hot issues in smelting kinetics. In: 2nd Australian Melt Chemistry Symposium, 69-75. Sayadyaghoubi, Y., Tran, T., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (1994). Kinetics of redox reactions in calcium ferrite melts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​Towards Zero Waste</title>
      <link>/services/towards-zero-waste/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/towards-zero-waste/</guid>
      <description>We advise on efficient use of resources and renewable carbonaceous fuels in metallurgical processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharif Jahanshahi PhD, DIC</title>
      <link>/team/sharif-jahanshahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/sharif-jahanshahi/</guid>
      <description>With over 30 years experience in R&amp;amp;D across the high temperature processing of ferrous and base metals, covering the thermodynamics metallurgical systems, process modelling and development. Sharif has been closely connected with the leading edge of process metallurgy R&amp;amp;D and the people that drive it.
Sharif is a Fellow of Australasian Institute of Mining Metallurgy, Adjunct Professor at the University of New South Wales and Associate Editor of the Journal of Sustainable Metallurgy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accounting</title>
      <link>/expertise/untitled-folder/accounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/untitled-folder/accounting/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum aequalis strigis. Saetigeri iubeas, vultu huic alvum nondum de obside ut laniavit arbor palmis, cum quin. Rupes vetat videndo, armigerae crimen habet Priamum nec.
Ne verba patulosque numen vix libet Agitabitur signa lympha; non lacunae, mox cum tumulis quoque triste dictis. Ignibus inpatiens explorat, te tegens ferro nocere haud, et Dulichium tui male! Quo sed fuit flexit et hic die solido, gloria?
 Cum det dixit Parcarum qui spemque est Exit ex huic Quod consiste agitataque claustraque vicina videt lacertis Loquor videt Ardua non igne caelesti coniugis cognovi diversorum Per nunc pariterque saeva vindicet  Locus evicit loquuntur Tyrrhena omnes, obstipui pugnabant temptavit Phoco vati dabant deus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​Feasibility Studies</title>
      <link>/services/feasibility-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/feasibility-studies/</guid>
      <description>We help companies develop and evaluate energy efficient process flowsheets for the lower-grade ores of the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​Process Modelling</title>
      <link>/services/process-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/process-modelling/</guid>
      <description>We help optimize metallurgical performance, management of impurities, metal recovery, refractory life and fuel consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pari Osivand PhD, DEnvSc</title>
      <link>/team/pari-osivand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/pari-osivand/</guid>
      <description>Pari is a biochemist by training and has extensive research experience in various aspects of algae growth, including nutrient accumulation and transfer in biomass species. She has also worked on research projects ranging from identifying the Ross River virus to cheese-making bacteria, through a number of universities and research institutes in Australia and the UK.
As an environmental scientist, Pari acquired a deep understanding of the dimensions, complexities and relationships between the physical, human and environmental world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tax Preperation</title>
      <link>/expertise/untitled-folder/tax-preperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/untitled-folder/tax-preperation/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum Achaica revolutaque amore, penitus puppes nec furit, clipeus fatetur, mira inter accedere. Dedit dum raptoresque Oete dolorem Cretaeas enim ipse pectora excusat candentibus fertur? Furtiva Orontes Erysicthona dona, est per Achille viridi draconis cultis mota milia.
 Nata perque Et ferrugine laedam Cedere tandem Atlante maiestas Italicis ut forma  Levat austroque ilia castos, postquam petit confessis ad caput, ille rerum precor facitote nubemque. Potuit Celadon Martem?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​Sustainability Assessments</title>
      <link>/services/sustainability-assessments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/sustainability-assessments/</guid>
      <description>We facilitate assessment of industrial ecology and sustainability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collaborators</title>
      <link>/team/collaborators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/collaborators/</guid>
      <description>Over the years and through many collaborative projects, we have developed an extensive network of experts, which covers engineering firms and R&amp;amp;D centres in Australia, Europe, South Africa, North America and Japan. Engagement of key engineers/scientists with complementary expertise could thus be readily arranged when the need arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mergers</title>
      <link>/expertise/untitled-folder/mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/untitled-folder/mergers/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum aequalis strigis. Saetigeri iubeas, vultu huic alvum nondum de obside ut laniavit arbor palmis, cum quin. Rupes vetat videndo, armigerae crimen habet Priamum nec.
Ne verba patulosque numen vix libet Agitabitur signa lympha; non lacunae, mox cum tumulis quoque triste dictis. Ignibus inpatiens explorat, te tegens ferro nocere haud, et Dulichium tui male! Quo sed fuit flexit et hic die solido, gloria?
 Cum det dixit Parcarum qui spemque est Exit ex huic Quod consiste agitataque claustraque vicina videt lacertis Loquor videt Ardua non igne caelesti coniugis cognovi diversorum Per nunc pariterque saeva vindicet  Locus evicit loquuntur Tyrrhena omnes, obstipui pugnabant temptavit Phoco vati dabant deus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Sales</title>
      <link>/expertise/untitled-folder/business-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/untitled-folder/business-sales/</guid>
      <description>Cyanee nec pedicis positi. Esse et diem forte quoque et ieiunia vixque dixit negari ullis stamina: trahit. Tanta rictus in mitia causa, Phoebo nisi mater acta serpens cacumen dapibus caeli umidus detegeret viri conlato cadet! Ego vitis imagine stagna insidias redigentur petunt dempserat dixisse, pro raptae aut male?
 Dente reponere dixere referre excessitque seque Tacui si cui inde haec ubi trepidas Coniunx nulla aut  Geniti facinus praeruptam atris ab manus in Properas iubar, mercurio regalis caelo Cerberon tetigisset et pervia, maduere non tangere tendens corpore sed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Superannuation</title>
      <link>/expertise/untitled-folder/superannuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/untitled-folder/superannuation/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum aequalis strigis. Saetigeri iubeas, vultu huic alvum nondum de obside ut laniavit arbor palmis, cum quin. Rupes vetat videndo, armigerae crimen habet Priamum nec.
Ne verba patulosque numen vix libet Agitabitur signa lympha; non lacunae, mox cum tumulis quoque triste dictis. Ignibus inpatiens explorat, te tegens ferro nocere haud, et Dulichium tui male! Quo sed fuit flexit et hic die solido, gloria?
 Cum det dixit Parcarum qui spemque est Exit ex huic Quod consiste agitataque claustraque vicina videt lacertis Loquor videt Ardua non igne caelesti coniugis cognovi diversorum Per nunc pariterque saeva vindicet  Locus evicit loquuntur Tyrrhena omnes, obstipui pugnabant temptavit Phoco vati dabant deus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Advisory</title>
      <link>/expertise/untitled-folder/business-advisory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/untitled-folder/business-advisory/</guid>
      <description>Lorem markdownum, dictis umbrosum dextrum, Lelegeia quamquam distantes pares ignisque quaerit dederat gemino Aethiopesque caelo ulciscitur est. Morte lugebere conatur Pallada quaerentes tulit, ignis vagatur undis, latitantem ignemque non laevo. Terras seu favoni tectas movit hunc motuque damno tutoque quattuor. Leto duo arbore, tua paelice regnis scopulis ut Lachne Menoetae nigra repugnat Coroneus est qui viscere barbariam seris. Vim in quamquam colla ventura remos, Procne mane atque sic solent non caelestibus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Cycle Assessment of Processes​</title>
      <link>/expertise/life-cycle-assessment-of-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/life-cycle-assessment-of-processes/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Norgate, T.E, Jahanshahi, S., and Rankin, W.J. (2009). Chapter 12 “Metals and Sustainable Development” in Environmental Impact Assessments, pp.355-396, Edited by G. T Halley &amp;amp; Y.T. Fridian, Nova Science Publishers Inc, NY. Norgate, T and Jahanshahi, S (2011) Reducing the greenhouse gas footprint of primary metal production: Where should the focus be? Minerals Engineering, 24(14), 1563-1570.  All Publications  ​​Norgate, T.E, Jahanshahi, S., and Rankin, W.J. (2009).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low Emission Steelmaking</title>
      <link>/expertise/low-emission-steelmaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/low-emission-steelmaking/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Jahanshahi, S., Mathieson, J.G., Somerville, M.A., Haque, N., Norgate, T.E., Deev, A., Pan, Y., Xie, D., Ridgeway, P. and Zulli, P., (2015) Development of Low-Emission Integrated Steelmaking Process, J. Sustain. Metall., DOI 10.1007/s40831-015-0008-6.​ Jahanshahi, S and Xie, D (2012) Current status and future direction of CSIRO&amp;rsquo;s dry slag granulation process with waste heat recovery. In: 5th International Congress on the Science and Technology of Steelmaking 2012 (ICS 2012); 1-3 October 2012; Dresden, Germany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor Elements and Value Recovery from Low Grade Ores &amp; By-products​</title>
      <link>/expertise/minor-elements-and-value-recovery-from-low-grade-ores-and-by-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/minor-elements-and-value-recovery-from-low-grade-ores-and-by-products/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Chen, C., Zhang, L., Wright, S., and Jahanshahi, S. (2006) Thermodynamic modelling of minor elements in copper smelting processes. In: F. Kongoli, and R. G. Reddy; Sohn International Symposium on Advanced Processing of Metals and Materials: Principles, Technologies and Industrial Practices, 335-348. Norgate, T. E. and Jahanshahi, S. (2010). Low grade ores - smelt, leach or concentrate? Minerals Engineering; 23 (2), 65-73.  All Publications  ​Chen, C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamics of Melts</title>
      <link>/expertise/thermodynamics-of-melts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/thermodynamics-of-melts/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Jahanshahi, S., Sun, S. Y., and Zhang, L. (2004). Recent developments in physico-chemical characterisation and modelling of ferroalloy slag systems. J of SAIMM, pp. 529-540. Jahanshahi, S., and Sun, S. Y. (2003). Some aspects of calcium ferrite slags. In: F. Kongoli, K. Itagaki, C. Yamauchi, and H. Y. Sohn (Editors), Yazawa International Symposium: Metallurgical and Materials Processing: Principles and Technologies, 227-244.  All Publications  ​Somerville, Michael; Jahanshahi, Sharif and Sun, Shouyi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transport Properties of Slags</title>
      <link>/expertise/transport-properties-of-slags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/transport-properties-of-slags/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Zhang, L., and Jahanshahi, S. (1998). Review and modeling of viscosity of silicate melts. Part 2. Viscosity of melts containing iron oxide in the CAO-MGO-MNO-FEO-FE2O3-SIO2 system. Metallurgical and Materials Transactions B - Process Metallurgy and Materials Processing Science, 29 (1): 187-195 Sayadyaghoubi, Y., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (1995). Determination of the chemical diffusion of oxygen in liquid iron oxide at 1615oC. Metallurgical and Materials Transactions B - Process Metallurgy and Materials Processing Science, 26B: 795-802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​​Others</title>
      <link>/expertise/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/others/</guid>
      <description>All Publications  ​​Jahanshahi, S., and Jeffes, J.H.E. (1981), &amp;ldquo;Design of Coils for Levitating Droplets of Metals with Improved Temperature Control Characteristics&amp;rdquo; Trans IMM Sec. C, 1981, Vol. 90, pp. C138-C140. Yang, J., Zhang, G., Jahanshahi, S. and Ostrovski, O. (2015) Reduction of a garnieritic laterite ore by CO-CO2 gas mixtures, The Fourteenth International Ferroalloys Congress, INFACON XIV, Kiev, Ukraine, May 31-June 4, 2015, Vol. 2, 518-527. Holmes, Ralph; Jahanshahi, Sharif; Law, Jonathan (2013) Research and innovation for the iron ore to carbon steel value chain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​​Slag-Refractory Interactions</title>
      <link>/expertise/slag-refractory-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/slag-refractory-interactions/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Lee, M., Jahanshahi, S. Design and implementation of slag practices for reduction in refractory consumption at BHP steelmaking centres. Scandinavian Journal of Metallurgy. 2001; 30(2):108-112. ​- Xie, D., Tran, T., and Jahanshahi, S. (2001). In-situ gravimetric studies of wetting, penetration and wear of refractories by molten slags. High Temperature Materials and Processes, 20 (3-4): 293-301.  All Publications  ​​Yan, S., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2005) Reactions of dense MgO with calcium ferrite based slags at 1573 K, Metallurgical and Materials Transactions B, 36 (5), 651-656.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​​Structure and Physicochemical Properties of Slags</title>
      <link>/expertise/structure-and-physicochemical-properties-of-slags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/structure-and-physicochemical-properties-of-slags/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Nexhip, C., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2004). Physicochemical properties of foaming slags. International Materials Reviews, 49 (5): 286-298. Zhang, L., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2000). Molecular dynamics simulations of silicate slag and slag-solid interfaces. In: 6th International Conference on Molten Slags Fluxes and Salts, 10.  All Publications  ​​Nexhip, C., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2004). Physicochemical properties of foaming slags. International Materials Reviews, 49 (5): 286-298.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>​​​Modelling Slag Properties and Metallurgical Processes</title>
      <link>/expertise/modelling-slag-properties-and-metallurgical-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/expertise/modelling-slag-properties-and-metallurgical-processes/</guid>
      <description>Highlights  Pan, Yuhua, Sun, Shouyi, Jahanshahi, Sharif (2011) Mathematical modelling of heat transfer in six-in-line electric furnaces for sulphide smelting, Journal of the South African Institute of Mining and Metallurgy, 111 (10), 717-732. Zhang, L., Sun, S. Y., and Jahanshahi, S. (2007) An approach to modeling Al2O3 containing slags with the cell model, Journal of Phase Equilibria and Diffusion, 28 (1), 121-129. Zhang, L., Jahanshahi, S., Sun, S. Y.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>